Ashley C. Lowe Mackenzie

ENVIRONMENTAL ECONOMIST

4969 MAUNALANI CIRCLE HONOLULU HAWAII 96816 5412706885 ALOWEMAC@HAWAII.EDU

Objective

I am an applied environmental economist specializing in the intersection of social and ecological systems, particularly in public lands and outdoor recreation. My research addresses emerging questions in outdoor recreation and public land management, including driving factors for demand, management strategies and various quantitative nonmarket valuation methods.

Education

2018-2023 **Oregon State University**

Ph.D. Applied Economics

Dissertation: "Understanding the New Outdoor Recreation Paradigm in the

Era of Social Media and Increasing Public Health Advisories"

Public Health Advisories" Link to dissertation

2017-2020

Oregon State University MS Applied Economics

Thesis: "Is Instagram Influencing Visitation to Public Lands?"

Advisor: Steven Dundas

2008-2011

Portland State University

BS Economic

Research Experience

2023-Current

Postdoctoral Fellow at University of Hawaii Manoa

This project is funded through NOAA Ocean Acidification Project. I am translating outputs of an ecological model into outcomes for Hawaii's people through the ecosystem provision of recreation and tourism. The focus is on identify spatial vulnerabilities across the island to improve community resilience.

The dataset of this project is exploring secondary data developed from the lab, reservation systems from DLNR and data from Department of Tourism Hawaii.

Work Schedule: 40hrs/week Supervisors: Kristen Oleson

2021-2022

Graduate Research Assistant at OSU

This project was funded by the Oregon Department of Transportation examining the potential impacts from highway infrastructure failures stemming from coastal erosion and sea level rise. For this analysis I used Oregon state park reservation data sets and visitor levels to public parks to estimate various potential impacts of adaptation strategies, including permanent beach width loss from coastal hardening, benefits and cost associated with access to amenity, as well as cost from added emissions from reroutes using the social cost of carbon.

The analysis uses both market and non-market values in a benefit cost analysis addressing. natural resource connections, community resilience through land-use planning, climate change vulnerability and adaptation. Collaborates with managers, policymakers, and scientists to produce research addressing the needs of natural resource managers, policymakers, and communities.

Work Schedule: 20hrs/week

Supervisors: Steven Dundas

Phone: (541) 737-1402

Summer 2019 Data Analyst at Oregon State Parks and Recreational Dept (OPRD)

Conducted field work on visitation to Oregon State Parks validating estimation methods for OPRD. I collected visitor counts and compared it to car counters at entrances of day use area. We also examined other visitator counting systems such as trail counters and newer traffic counter monitoring systems.

Disseminates research results to peers and park managers.

Work Schedule: 40hrs/week Supervisors: Caleb Dickson Phone: 503-428-8790

Teaching experience

2023 Western Oregon University Instructor

Department of Sustainability

SUS 390 Global Climate Change On-campus

Course covering climate science using IPCC AR6, adaptation & mitigation strategies, historical climate policies, carbon wealth inequalities, economics, Social Cost of Carbon and carbon pricing.

Developed lectures, quizzes, exams, and homework

• SUS 340 Sustainability & Capitalism Ecampus Currently designing course covering pillars of sustainability & capitalism framework. I use UN Sustainability Development Goals to examine the how the pillars and incentives of capitalism fit within the framework.

Developed lectures, quizzes, exams, and homework

2020 **Oregon State University Instructor**

Department of Applied Economics

• AEC 253 Environmental Law, Policy and Economics Ecampus

2018-2021 **Oregon State University Teaching Assistant**

Applied Economic and Sustainability Departments

- AEC 253 Environmental Law, Policy and Economics Ecampus
- AEC 525 Applied Econometrics
 - Graduate level lab teaching econometric commands in STATA
- AEC 447 Agriculture Price and Market Analysis
- AEC/ECON 432 Environmental Law Ecampus & On-campus
- AEC 388 Agricultural Law Ecampus & On-campus
- AEC/ECON 352 Environmental Economics and Policy
- SUS 350 Sustainability Communities (3quarters) Ecampus
 - Including a role in developing a new canvas course material on Canvas.
- SUS 304 Sustainability Assessment (3quarters) Ecampus
- AEC 253 Environmental Law, Policy and Economics (3quarters) Ecampus & On-campus
 - In-class conducting Pollution Control Games, highlighting the difference between command and control, taxes, and Cap & Trade.
- AEC 122 Introduction to Climate Change Economics and Policy Ecampus & On-campus

Publications

Journal publications

Lowe Mackenzie, A., S. J. Dundas, and B. Zhao. *The Instagram Effect: Is Social Media Influencing Visitation to Public Land?* Land Economics. DOI: https://doi.org/10.3368/le.100.2.122920-0192R1

2022 Working Paper

Olsen, M. J., J Allan, S. J. Dundas, A. Lowe Mackenzie, M. Krivova, A. Senogles, B. A. Leshchinsky, J. Hermann, and C. Parrish. US Highway 101 Coastal Hazard Vulnerability and Assessment for Mitigation Prioritization, Oregon Department of Transportation Project, Federal Highway Administration, Project SPR-843.

Lowe Mackenzie, A., S.J. Dundas. Is a Photo Worth 1,000 Likes? The Influence of Instagram at National Parks *Link*

Current Work in Progress

The Effects of Public Health Advisories on the Value of Recreational Camping

Modeling ecosystem service changes due to OA and associated social vulnerability $\,$

Estimating the Impacts of Removing Oregon's Severance Tax on Large Industrial Timber Harvesting

Presentations 2023 Camp Resources Is a Photo Worth 1,000 Likes? Visitation Modeling and Influence of Instagram at National Parks Aug. 8 2023 2020 **People and Nature At OSU** Is Instagram Influencing Visitation to Public Lands? 2022 **Graduate Teaching Seminar Professional Oregon State University** training Description: focuses on evidence-based pedagogical practices with an emphasis on practical strategies and problem-solving, and will be tuned to graduate students' needs and the classes they are instructing. 2019 **Training Social Justice Education Initiative Workshop** Description: Apply a vocabulary of basic terms in common with other participants. Recognize how history relates to the current context of Oregon and OSU. Describe some of your own social identities. Recognize that your OSU community is comprised of diverse and intersecting social identities. Understand that a dominant culture exists, even if it is invisible to you. **Computer skills** Programming Python, R, HTML, markdown, JavaScript, CSS Visual Studio Code, QGIS, Rstudio, Latex, Anaconda, Stata, Applications ArcGis, Final Cut, Matlab, Git, Github, Google Cloud • File Directories: macOS, Microsoft Windows, Ubuntu/Unix Libraries • JavaScript: D3.js, C3.js, bootstrap, Leaflet, JQuery, dc.js • R: tidyverse, NLP, dplyr, tidyr, ggplot2, tidytext • Python: pandas, pip, NumPy, Matplotlib, NLK, spaCy

References Dr. Steven Dundas Advisor Department of Applied Economics – Oregon State University Phone: (541) 737-1402 • Advisor Chair & CoAuthor

Dr. Ashley Department of Forest Ecosystems & Society – Oregon State University Phone: (541) 737-5043

Committee • Committee Member

Advisor for recreation ecology concentration

<u>Dr. Nadia A.</u> Department of Applied Economics – Oregon State University Phone: <u>Streletskaya</u> (347) 735.1787

Committee • Advisor for behavioral economics concentration

Dr. KirstenDept. of Natural Resources & Environmental Management – UniversityOlesonof Hawaii at Manoa Phone: (808)956.8864Post Doc PIPost Doc PI on Ocean Acidification